<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>On a Wooden Block</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://onawoodenblock.com/</id><updated>2021-06-04T17:43:00+03:00</updated><subtitle>Tea freak, teaware admirer and keyboard masher.</subtitle><entry><title>Why is Vim so important for programmers.</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/why-is-vim-so-important-for-programmers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-04T17:43:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-06-04T17:43:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-06-04:/why-is-vim-so-important-for-programmers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Why do I think vim is the greatest tool for any programmer.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;emsp;So then, why is Vim so goddamn great? And why do a lot of programmers talk about it?
There are a ton of articles as to why Vim is indispensable, but I'm gonna tell it to you simple and easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;emsp;I don't use vim, I don't like vim. Vim is hard and it takes too much to make it how I want.
I also use Windows mostly, so I find any vim implementation to have a slow startup and if I want to use the terminal it's sometimes buggy (looking at you cmd).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;emsp;That's why I use is Sublime Text with the NeoVintageous plugin.
I get the rich plugin ecosystem of sublime, with the advantage of vim (in 99% of cases).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does vim work? Well, vim has a thing called modes.&lt;br&gt;
When you start the editor you're put in "normal" mode.&lt;br&gt;
You press &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;I&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;o&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;O&lt;/code&gt; and you're put in "insert" mode where you... well... insert.&lt;br&gt;
To leave insert mode, you press &lt;code&gt;escape&lt;/code&gt;, and you'll be put you back in "normal" mode.&lt;br&gt;
You press &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;V&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;ctrl+v&lt;/code&gt; and you're put in "visual" mode. With visual mode, you select without using your mouse.&lt;br&gt;
You press &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt; to enter command-line mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you want to select 5 lines &lt;code&gt;V5j&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Imagine you want to select upwards without losing what you've already selected &lt;code&gt;o5k&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;emsp;The main point of vim is... stop using your mouse, it's a pain in the ass to move from keyboard to mouse to keyboard to mouse again and again when everything is so easy to do without the mouse.&lt;br&gt;
Also, why would you ever want to be in "insert" mode all the time, you lose so many possibilities for movement if you're 24/7 in insert mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;emsp;Traditional text editors work like this, they start in "insert" mode and then you have only a limited number of possible movements.&lt;br&gt;
You can move with the mouse, select with the mouse and drag and drop (not like anyone uses that... right?).&lt;br&gt;
Then you have the arrow keys, end/home, page up/page down, ctrl+arrow keys (in some editors even alt+arrow keys), and that's all.&lt;br&gt;
And if you want to select, use those movements while holding shift, which is quite painful from time to time. You can of course, select with mouse. With vim, you just enter insert mode and use all the movement keys like you'd do normally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;emsp;But what if I told you, that you can use vim in any, or better said in most of the modern editors.&lt;br&gt;
Most of them will already have a plugin that emulates or even integrates neovim (vim rewritten by other people).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every key in normal mode does a different thing. For example, if you want to move left down up right you use h j k l. You can also use arrow keys, nobody stops you.&lt;br&gt;
To enter insert mode, as I said, there are at least 6 keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;o&lt;/code&gt; inserts a new line below and puts you into insert mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;O&lt;/code&gt; inserts a new line above and puts you into insert mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; starts insert mode before the cursor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; starts insert mode after the cursor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;I&lt;/code&gt; stars insert mode at the beginning of the line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; starts insert mode at the end of the line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;emsp;Vim also makes those keys easy to remember. And once your get over your initial fear of learning vim, you won't be able to live without it, seriously.&lt;br&gt;
Vim does commands, and those commands are easy to compose.&lt;br&gt;
To delete one line you use &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt;, what if you want to delete 5 lines? &lt;code&gt;5dd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
What if you want to delete 5 lines downwards &lt;code&gt;5dd&lt;/code&gt; (same as &lt;code&gt;5dd&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;d4j&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;br&gt;
What about upwards &lt;code&gt;d4k&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;4dk&lt;/code&gt; (4 is not a mistake, I'll explain). Those commands translate to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; means delete whole line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;5dd&lt;/code&gt;) means repeat the command 5 times. Aka, delete 5 lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; is the prefix for a command, that's why when you just press &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; in normal mode, it doesn't do anything until you press another key (or &lt;code&gt;escape&lt;/code&gt; to cancel). If you press &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; in visual mode when you have already selected something, that will simply delete the selected text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;d4j&lt;/code&gt; now, why 4? Well, when you do &lt;code&gt;dj&lt;/code&gt; it deletes the current line AND the line below. It literally translates to "delete" this line and the line below (for &lt;code&gt;d4j&lt;/code&gt; it's this line and the 4 lines below). If you do &lt;code&gt;4j&lt;/code&gt; it'll move you 4 lines below, exactly where all of those lines would be deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of h j k l you can use arrow keys, but it's easier to have your hands on hjkl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now... I lied, &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; doesn't delete, but it's easy to remember it as &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt;elete. It actually cuts text, and it puts it in the "unnamed register". Now, I won't talk about registers because the extensions usually use the system clipboard which is the best usecase in my opinion. You can paste in vim with &lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; (paste after cursor)/&lt;code&gt;P&lt;/code&gt; (paste before cursor).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can move not just letters, but words as well.&lt;br&gt;
For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt; jump to the start of the next word&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;W&lt;/code&gt; jump to the start of the next word (ignore punctuation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; jump to the end of the words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt; jump to the end of the words (ignore punctuation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; jump to the beginning of the words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;B&lt;/code&gt; jump to the beginning of the words (ignore punctuation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also move by paragraphs &lt;code&gt;{&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;}&lt;/code&gt;, move to matching paranthesis/brackets &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt;elete, &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt;ank (copy), &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt;hange (same as delete but puts you in insert mode afterwards), using the movement commands. &lt;code&gt;d5w&lt;/code&gt; (delete 5 words), &lt;code&gt;d5b&lt;/code&gt; (delete 5 words backwards).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And my favourite thing in vim, &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;n and &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt;round.&lt;br&gt;
Assume you have a &lt;code&gt;function foo(var_a, var_b, var_c)&lt;/code&gt; and your cursor is on &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;var_b&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
You want to get rid of all parameters and rewrite them &lt;code&gt;ci(&lt;/code&gt;, which translates to "change in  ()", what if I want to also delete the paranthesis? &lt;code&gt;ca(&lt;/code&gt; "change around ()".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the word &lt;code&gt;very_long_word_holy_guacamole&lt;/code&gt;, and I my cursor is on &lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;word&lt;/code&gt;. Without vim I'd do &lt;code&gt;ctrl+right ctrl+backspace&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ctrl+right shift+ctrl+left delete/backspace&lt;/code&gt;, with vim I do &lt;code&gt;ciw&lt;/code&gt; "change in word".&lt;br&gt;
Every movement command can be used in combination with &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt;elete, &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt;ank, &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt;hange, &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt;isual, etc. Every command can be combined with the movement keys.
Now then, all of those were written from memory, it's easy to remember the commands once you use them, and it's a heck of a lot of fun doing so.&lt;br&gt;
There's also &lt;code&gt;ctrl+o&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;ctrl+i&lt;/code&gt; to move to last cursor position and back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My point is, vim is superior to the traditional way of editing text (aka only "insert" mode).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you entered vim and can't exit it, you can exit it from normal mode or command mode.&lt;br&gt;
The traditional way is in normal mode you press &lt;code&gt;:q&lt;/code&gt; and enter.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt; stands for command-line mode, &lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt; stands for quit. Also &lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt; stands for write, so if you want to save and exit &lt;code&gt;:wq&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;:x&lt;/code&gt; (x is a bit different though, it won't write if no change occured).&lt;br&gt;
If you want to quit without saving &lt;code&gt;:q!&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Now you can also quit or save without pressing &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt;, which is &lt;code&gt;ZZ&lt;/code&gt; (equivalent to &lt;code&gt;:x&lt;/code&gt;) or &lt;code&gt;ZQ&lt;/code&gt; (equivalent to &lt;code&gt;:q!&lt;/code&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you want to learn it, there's a good unix command (once you installed vim) called &lt;code&gt;vimtutor&lt;/code&gt;. It's there in wsl or any unix based operating system, might even be on windows if you install gvim.&lt;br&gt;
If you don't want to learn it &lt;code&gt;¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="editor"></category><category term="vim"></category><category term="sublime"></category></entry><entry><title>I love cracks.</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/i-love-cracks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-30T00:03:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-04-30T00:03:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-04-30:/i-love-cracks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Waterglass and Iron Oxide, quick showoff.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, throughout my adventures with clay, I started playing with waterglass.&lt;br&gt;
I go to a workshop for ceramics and the person in charge, Andras, told me about it.&lt;br&gt;
So, I gave it a test round, came out quite great, and so I decided to make myself a chawan with the accumulated knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also love iron oxide (rust), I feel like it adds to the aestetique of age.&lt;br&gt;
I'm deeply, let me repeat myself, deeply in love with the philosophy and aestetique of wabi-sabi, and that's the style I pursue in my cups.&lt;br&gt;
I want them to feel raw, imperfect, not too complicated, not too simple. Fortunately, I haven't yet found it, I'm still in the pursuit of it, and I'm saying fortunately because the journey towards the perfect style is a heck of a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then, short intro, here are the cups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First try, to see what can iron oxide and waterglass do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/waterglass_test.jpg" width="760"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is the second cup. After seeing what I can do with it, this is one of the works I'm proud of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/chawan_waterglass.jpg" width="760"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you like them!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Teaware"></category><category term="chawan"></category><category term="teaware"></category></entry><entry><title>My very first teacup</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/my-very-first-teacup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-18T12:08:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T12:08:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-04-18:/my-very-first-teacup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A story about my first teacup.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As written in a &lt;a href="/my-tea-journey.html"&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, because of tea and a &lt;a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/9996/Hyouge_Mono"&gt;certain anime&lt;/a&gt; I became obsessed with making my own teaware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, looking for ceramic workshops in Cluj. Somehow, I find one and I muster up my courage to go for a visit.&lt;br&gt;
I put myself on a chair and the guy in charge (we'll call him A) starts explaning about everything and guides me through every step in making a beautiful teacup.&lt;br&gt;
He tells me to start with a technique called "nerikomi", make a salami combining clays, then cut pieces, put them side by side to form a rectangle and then press it into a predefined form. Pressing it into a "biscuit" ceramic bowl is the easiest way of achieving a form. It's fired at 800-1000 degrees celsius and it absorbs moisture, so once I put in into form, it can easily separate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's what I do, I'm given multiple clays with similar shrinkage. Clay shrinks after moisture evaporates and if you make nerikomi and the shrinkage is too different, it will separate either when drying or biscuiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make a rectangle using white, brown and some black, and start pressing it into form, being VERY careful not to break anything. Afterwards I put a little circle foot on the bottom of the cup and with that three hours have passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, I await the next workshop which is two weeks later. The workshop used to be held twice a month before transitioning to twice a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next workshop comes, I carefully sandpaper the cup and make the form of another cup (which I probably won't talk about, didn't come out that great).&lt;br&gt;
And so, another two weeks pass, my cup was fired at 850&amp;deg;C and now it's time to glaze it. Because it's my very first cup and I want to see the pattern so I use a transparent glaze.&lt;br&gt;
Another two weeks, my cup is fired at 1200&amp;deg;C and it's finally ready. I can take it home and enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the story, it took quite a while to finish the cup, and I put at least 5 hours in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/first_cup1.jpg" width="760"&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/first_cup2.jpg" width="760"&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/first_cup3.jpg" width="760"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Teaware"></category><category term="teaware"></category><category term="teacup"></category></entry><entry><title>My tea journey</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/my-tea-journey.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-17T13:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-04-17T13:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-04-17:/my-tea-journey.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The story of tea and me.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Throughout my life, the only thing I knew about tea was that green tea is for losing weight and black tea is bitter.&lt;br&gt;
My mom told me those things, and the only tea we'd ever drink was mint tea with a ton of lemon and honey. Nowadays, thinking back, it was kind of a hot lemonade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I used to watch TV with my dad and from time to time there would be some Chinese movie where they'd drink tea. I liked the idea and look of it, but never put more thought into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in highschool I watched an anime called &lt;a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/4898/Kuroshitsuji"&gt;Kuroshitsuji&lt;/a&gt; and there was a scene where the master asks for tea from his butler, but not any tea, it was Earl Grey.&lt;br&gt;
The butler goes in the basement, brings the tea and makes him a cup. Mind you, I have NEVER heard even once, the name of the tea. I never had any tangency with the subject of tea except from what I wrote above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thrilled, I have to try this I thought... But can I even find it in Romania? And how expensive such a thing can be? The name is posh af.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the not so distant future, I went to Kaufland with my mom in search of Earl Grey, it doesn't hurt to give it a shot, might actually find it in the supermarket.&lt;br&gt;
Found the tea section and there it was... &lt;a href="/images/dukat_earl_grey.webp"&gt;Dukat Earl Grey&lt;/a&gt; teabags, 2-3 ron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What?! So cheap? I was both happy and scared, overly cheap things surely compromise a lot on quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went home and was still excited to try it. My mom told me to be careful because it's bitter.&lt;br&gt;
Of course that didn't stop me.
I boiled some water, put the teabag and waited 3 minutes (that's what was written on the box).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the long awaited time, I gave it a sip. Wasn't anything spectacular, a tad bit bitter, not too much taste.&lt;br&gt;
What if I add some sugar? I put 1-2 teaspoons of sugar and tried it again... WOAH! Fell in love with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months pass, I become increasingly more into tea (with sugar) and buy almost every type of tea from the supermarkets to try it out.&lt;br&gt;
Lipton, Twinnings, Dukat, Taylors of Harrogate and all those big/little brands, I've tried quite a number, I liked them. I tried senchas, Earl Grey, Lady Grey, Breakfast Tea, gunpowder, and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the 12th grade (last year of highschool) I met somebody on the internet, on a site for anime quotes. He was looking for people to help with the coding of the site. php, HTML and CSS, the things I had to learn that year. I thought it would be a good learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking/playing/coding for a few months with him, we became good friends, and I found out that he drinks tea as well, but only thyme tea.&lt;br&gt;
In the past I used to want to like the things the people I looked up to liked. And because I looked up to this person, tea became an even more important part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highschool ends and here comes university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reach a time where I drink a few cups per day while working on projects and staying in front of my laptop.&lt;br&gt;
I think to myself, I love tea, but if I have each cup with one to two teaspoons of sugar per day, it won't do well for me later on. So I completely remove the sugar, and surprisingly, I enjoy it. I grew to yearn for the bitter flavors of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey of collecting and trying out new teas does not stop. Months pass, I have a full cabinet worth of teas. Mostly teabags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanting to learn more about the types of tea and how they are made, I stumble on a Youtube channel called &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCaHBABJFMRAtnKhQp2Cu5BQ"&gt;Meileaf&lt;/a&gt;, and on their video called &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EUuw5rqWkZU"&gt;The 6 Types Of Tea&lt;/a&gt;. I watch more of their videos and find out about a thing called "Gong Fu Tea", and I want to try it very much. They also have made me become a purist, back then &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-fZclzJUhYg"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; didn't exist, but it's exactly the message I got from a lot of their videos.&lt;br&gt;
It was around that time that my girlfriend moved from Hungary to Romania to live with me and started working at Demmers in Cluj.&lt;br&gt;
Because of Demmers I had the chance to try good loose leaf tea, and not the prepackaged, stale, old (not in a good way) teas from supermarkets. For that, I thank them.&lt;br&gt;
From them also, I bought my first gaiwan, a simple white porcelain, and so I had the chance to try gong-fu, from that moment on Western style tea disappeared from my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was not enough, I wanted more. What if Demmers is not the gold standard of teas, what if there are better teas out there? I can't just blindly accept that I have found the end of my tea journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately it was not the end, &lt;a href="https://white2tea.com/"&gt;white2tea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://yunnansourcing.com/"&gt;Yunnan Sourcing&lt;/a&gt; (when they used to ship to Romania, last time I looked they didn't anymore), &lt;a href="https://nioteas.com/"&gt;NioTeas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.hibiki-an.com/"&gt;Hibiki-an&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://eco-cha.com/"&gt;eco-cha&lt;/a&gt; and the list goes on and on.&lt;br&gt;
Don't get me wrong though, Demmers doesn't have bad teas. They're affordable and you can find them in Cluj. And if your life doesn't depend on tea, they're a very good choice.&lt;br&gt;
But if you're like me and life literally revolves around tea, it's not the end goal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very good book that thought me a lot about teas was &lt;a href="https://www.bookdepository.com/Tea-Kevin-Gascoyne/9780228100270"&gt;Tea: History, Terroirs, Varieties&lt;/a&gt;. I also linked my favourite site to buy books from, free worldwide delivery, they're a life saver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, my journey has not ended, I have to personally go to those countries, and try the teas, brewed in their local spring waters, freshly picked, freshly roasted, take part of the process, learn more and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because tea was such an important thing in my life, I started collecting teaware, gaiwans, cups, teapots.&lt;br&gt;
So, one day, I was looking for movies/series/anime about tea, and I found it: &lt;a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/9996/Hyouge_Mono"&gt;Hyouge Mono&lt;/a&gt;. It's an anime with tea, but the main focus is teaware. I was thrilled by how they described teaware.&lt;br&gt;
What if... I make my own? I have a profound connection with tea, why shouldn't I share the connection with teaware?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, after a few weeks of looking, researching, I found a ceramic workshop in Cluj. I gathered my courage and paid a visit. I instantly became a regular.&lt;br&gt;
My first cup (I'll talk about it in a later post) was a success in my opinion, and so I made cups over cups over cups. With that, I've found my purpose in life.&lt;br&gt;
That after I die, I leave a few pieces of teaware that somebody will put his hands on and say "that's beautiful".
That's what I want to leave behind, beauty in the form of a teacup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I can go to the workshop only once a week, and now because of some works around the area I can't go until the end of August. That is way too little, it's not remotely enough to even have dreams, yet alone, achieve them. I want to spend tens of years, hours a day, practicing. That's the only way it can ever be good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, the end goal is, a studio of my own where I can spend hours a day, and a kiln. And who knows, probably a teashop where people can enjoy drinking from my cups.&lt;br&gt;
It will take quite a few years to achieve my dream, but it's a clear path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope it was a good read!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tea"></category><category term="about"></category><category term="tea"></category><category term="teaware"></category></entry><entry><title>Kimchi</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/kimchi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-01T23:19:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-04-01T23:19:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-04-01:/kimchi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My take on kimchi&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, the time has arrived that I talk about Kimchi.
It's great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all, see ya!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright alright, how do you make kimchi. I'm by no means a chef or anything, but I like kimchi. And if I want to buy it from my local asian store... it's HELLISHLY expesive.
Imagine 10 eur for 200-300g of kimchi.
Where when I make my own with around 5 eur for around 3kg.
Also, homemade is way better, I'm serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a shit ton of kimchi recipes around the internet but I'll share with you my take on it and the experiences I've had with it.
I usually don't use rice flour for the paste, because apple/onion have enough bulk, and the rice doesn't really do much imho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rice flour alternative tho, &lt;a href="https://www.maangchi.com/"&gt;Maangchi&lt;/a&gt; has a good &lt;a href="https://www.maangchi.com/recipe/easy-kimchi"&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very first kimchi recipe I tried (and the one I am mostly going with) was from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChBEbMKI1eCcejTtmI32UEw"&gt;Joshua Weismann&lt;/a&gt; and it was &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aXhJcdXPyYI"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;. The recipe is also on his blog (&lt;a href="https://www.joshuaweissman.com/post/kimchi"&gt;https://www.joshuaweissman.com/post/kimchi&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be substituted in his recipe are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;daikon radishes (aka white radish) for black radish (cut them thinner though, they have a special spiciness to them) or even simple radish (cut it thin as well)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asian pear for an apple or normal pear, lol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes when you really can't find spring onions/chives...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leek also works (but barely).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what you can add are yellow onions, they work very well in the sauce.
For grams, look at the blog post of Joshua Weismann, it's a good starting point, you don't have to be too accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually my choice of ingredients are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Napa Cabbage: 2 big pieces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iodine Free Salt: enough, you'll see later on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carrots: 2 medium/big pieces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White raddish: 1/2 piece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green onions: around 6-7 medium pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR chives: a lot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for the paste:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apple: 1 medium/large&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or/and pear, you can do either or both really&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yellow onion: 1 medium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;garlic: ~30g-50g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ginger: ~50g-60g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fish sauce: ~60ml-70ml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;optional: one tsp of shrimp paste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;korean red pepper flakes: ~80g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly important to have good pepper flakes that taste good (ideally gochugaru, aka korean red pepper flakes), not just seeds that are JUST spicy. It also helps with the color, the beautiful red color can't be achieved with seeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be skipped in my opinion are the radishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well then, how do you make kimchi. I highly suggest watching Joshua Weismann's &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aXhJcdXPyYI"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; and making his, and then if you want extra steps, here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a first try, I suggest cutting the cabbage as shown in the video, &lt;a href="images/kimchi_bite_size.jpg"&gt;bite size pieces&lt;/a&gt;, it'll be easier.
Shove them in a bowl and salt them heavily, think oversalted, and add a bit more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let the cabbage sit for around 4 hours. (ideally this much, but if you're in a hurry you can do even 1 hour)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Until then, prepare the other vegetables, cut things in strips, if they're too thin you won't feel a bite to them. I usually do something like &lt;a href="images/cut_names.jpg"&gt;julienne&lt;/a&gt;. If you're using black radish, cut it to &lt;a href="images/cut_names.jpg"&gt;fine julienne&lt;/a&gt;, or if you enjoy the taste, bigger. The veggies of one of my batches were cut like &lt;a href="images/kimchi_pieces.jpg"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shove the ingredients for the paste in a food processor and make the paste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/strong&gt;: Add all the ingredients &lt;strong&gt;EXCEPT&lt;/strong&gt; the red pepper flakes, otherwise the paste will be too dry and the food processor will struggle. Combine the red pepper flakes only at the end after the paste is done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the cabbage soaked for 4 hours or however much you decided to let it, wash it thoroughly under running water to wash all the excess salt. The amount of salt that we need is already absorbed in the cabbage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine everything and put in a glass jar, or plastic box (food safe and BPA free) and push it down so to pack it tightly. Cover with lid, burp every 2 or so days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can of course eat some of the kimchi right away. Let the rest stay happily outside at room temperature to ferment for around 3-7 days (taste at 3rd day and see if you like the amount of acidity) and then let it rest in the fridge for around a week and you'll have the best kimchi possible. After the taste at day 3, you can decide if it's acidic enough or has fermented enough, if it doesn't have any acidity, let it out more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long does it stay in the fridge? I'd say definitely at least 6 months, even a year. It does become more acidic with time, because it ferments more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can you do with the kimchi? I usually eat from it when making rice bowls, you can stir-fry it, make a stew with it or when you need an acidic companion for other dishes.
It goes on a lot of things, it's seriously delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does fermentation work? We'll explore that some other time, I have to talk about it quite a bit, I'm in love with it. But I can't ever explain it better than the book &lt;a href="https://www.bookdepository.com/Art-Fermentation-Sandor-Ellix-Katz/9781603582865"&gt;The Art of Fermentation by Sandor Katz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's my take on kimchi, it's worth trying it at least once in your life, I fell in love instantly (I usually fall in love with fermented foods, so it's not new). If you want something easier, I'd suggest sauerkraut (salt, cabbage and patience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around one year ago (3rd of April 2020) I made a batch of kimchi, and I apparently took pictures. ![[Pasted image images/IMG_20210919_194702.jpg]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you like it, let me know how it came out at: &lt;a href="mailto:rexu@onawoodenblock.com"&gt;rexu@onawoodenblock.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Food"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="fermentation"></category><category term="recipe"></category></entry><entry><title>About</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/about.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-03-24T00:15:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-03-24T00:15:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-03-24:/about.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short summary to what this blog is about.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, what is this blog about...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make a blog, so I made it.
I'll put food reviews, cooking, coding, ceramics, and whatever I feel the need to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make my own tea cups and so, I'd like to put them all here one day.
The aestetic I'm going towards is wabi-sabi, all my cups need a touch of irregularity, imperfection and rawness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently rent a place with some people and have our own workshop.
But later in life I want to have my own place to enjoy creating beauties to no end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I might open an online shop for cups, but that remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work as a Software Engineer so there'll be a category dedicated to coding and stuff, depends if I find anything interesting enough to write and nobody has already written about it, because coding blogs are quite a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm writing it in English because I like English, and it offers the possibility for the hundreds of thousands of people awaiting to read my blog to actually be able to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that's about it, see ya!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit 12.08.2023: I actually currently co-own a pottery studio, but haven't updated the blog in quite a while, maybe will never do so. We'll see. No site tho.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="News"></category><category term="about"></category><category term="news"></category></entry></feed>