<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>On a Wooden Block - News</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/feeds/news.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://onawoodenblock.com/</id><updated>2021-03-24T00:15:00+02:00</updated><subtitle>Tea freak, teaware admirer and keyboard masher.</subtitle><entry><title>About</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/about.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-03-24T00:15:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-03-24T00:15:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-03-24:/about.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short summary to what this blog is about.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, what is this blog about...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in Cluj-Napoca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make a blog, so I made it.
I'll put food reviews (mostly orders, cause I don't really leave my house), cooking, coding, ceramics, and whatever I feel the need to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make my own tea cups and so, I'd like to put them all here one day.
The aestetic I'm going towards is wabi-sabi, all my cups need a touch of irregularity, imperfection and rawness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't own a kiln or studio yet, I'm just visiting a workshop once a week.
But I do want and will have a kiln and a place to enjoy creating beauties to no end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I might open an online shop for cups, but that remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work as a Software Engineer so there'll be a category dedicated to coding and stuff, depends if I find anything interesting enough to write and nobody has already written about it, because coding blogs are quite a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm writing it in English because I like English, and it offers the possibility for the hundreds of thousands of people awaiting to read my blog to actually be able to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that's about it, see ya!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="News"></category><category term="about"></category><category term="news"></category></entry></feed>