<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>On a Wooden Block - Tea</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/feeds/tea.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://onawoodenblock.com/</id><updated>2021-04-17T13:00:00+03:00</updated><subtitle>Tea freak, teaware admirer and keyboard masher.</subtitle><entry><title>My tea journey</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/my-tea-journey.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-17T13:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-04-17T13:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-04-17:/my-tea-journey.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The story of tea and me.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Throughout my life, the only thing I knew about tea was that green tea is for losing weight and black tea is bitter.&lt;br&gt;
My mom told me those things, and the only tea we'd ever drink was mint tea with a ton of lemon and honey. Nowadays, thinking back, it was kind of a hot lemonade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I used to watch TV with my dad and from time to time there would be some Chinese movie where they'd drink tea. I liked the idea and look of it, but never put more thought into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in highschool I watched an anime called &lt;a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/4898/Kuroshitsuji"&gt;Kuroshitsuji&lt;/a&gt; and there was a scene where the master asks for tea from his butler, but not any tea, it was Earl Grey.&lt;br&gt;
The butler goes in the basement, brings the tea and makes him a cup. Mind you, I have NEVER heard even once, the name of the tea. I never had any tangency with the subject of tea except from what I wrote above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thrilled, I have to try this I thought... But can I even find it in Romania? And how expensive such a thing can be? The name is posh af.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the not so distant future, I went to Kaufland with my mom in search of Earl Grey, it doesn't hurt to give it a shot, might actually find it in the supermarket.&lt;br&gt;
Found the tea section and there it was... &lt;a href="/images/dukat_earl_grey.webp"&gt;Dukat Earl Grey&lt;/a&gt; teabags, 2-3 ron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What?! So cheap? I was both happy and scared, overly cheap things surely compromise a lot on quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went home and was still excited to try it. My mom told me to be careful because it's bitter.&lt;br&gt;
Of course that didn't stop me.
I boiled some water, put the teabag and waited 3 minutes (that's what was written on the box).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the long awaited time, I gave it a sip. Wasn't anything spectacular, a tad bit bitter, not too much taste.&lt;br&gt;
What if I add some sugar? I put 1-2 teaspoons of sugar and tried it again... WOAH! Fell in love with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months pass, I become increasingly more into tea (with sugar) and buy almost every type of tea from the supermarkets to try it out.&lt;br&gt;
Lipton, Twinnings, Dukat, Taylors of Harrogate and all those big/little brands, I've tried quite a number, I liked them. I tried senchas, Earl Grey, Lady Grey, Breakfast Tea, gunpowder, and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the 12th grade (last year of highschool) I met somebody on the internet, on a site for anime quotes. He was looking for people to help with the coding of the site. php, HTML and CSS, the things I had to learn that year. I thought it would be a good learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking/playing/coding for a few months with him, we became good friends, and I found out that he drinks tea as well, but only thyme tea.&lt;br&gt;
In the past I used to want to like the things the people I looked up to liked. And because I looked up to this person, tea became an even more important part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highschool ends and here comes university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reach a time where I drink a few cups per day while working on projects and staying in front of my laptop.&lt;br&gt;
I think to myself, I love tea, but if I have each cup with one to two teaspoons of sugar per day, it won't do well for me later on. So I completely remove the sugar, and surprisingly, I enjoy it. I grew to yearn for the bitter flavors of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey of collecting and trying out new teas does not stop. Months pass, I have a full cabinet worth of teas. Mostly teabags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanting to learn more about the types of tea and how they are made, I stumble on a Youtube channel called &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCaHBABJFMRAtnKhQp2Cu5BQ"&gt;Meileaf&lt;/a&gt;, and on their video called &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EUuw5rqWkZU"&gt;The 6 Types Of Tea&lt;/a&gt;. I watch more of their videos and find out about a thing called "Gong Fu Tea", and I want to try it very much. They also have made me become a purist, back then &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-fZclzJUhYg"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; didn't exist, but it's exactly the message I got from a lot of their videos.&lt;br&gt;
It was around that time that my girlfriend moved from Hungary to Romania to live with me and started working at Demmers in Cluj.&lt;br&gt;
Because of Demmers I had the chance to try good loose leaf tea, and not the prepackaged, stale, old (not in a good way) teas from supermarkets. For that, I thank them.&lt;br&gt;
From them also, I bought my first gaiwan, a simple white porcelain, and so I had the chance to try gong-fu, from that moment on Western style tea disappeared from my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was not enough, I wanted more. What if Demmers is not the gold standard of teas, what if there are better teas out there? I can't just blindly accept that I have found the end of my tea journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately it was not the end, &lt;a href="https://white2tea.com/"&gt;white2tea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://yunnansourcing.com/"&gt;Yunnan Sourcing&lt;/a&gt; (when they used to ship to Romania, last time I looked they didn't anymore), &lt;a href="https://nioteas.com/"&gt;NioTeas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.hibiki-an.com/"&gt;Hibiki-an&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://eco-cha.com/"&gt;eco-cha&lt;/a&gt; and the list goes on and on.&lt;br&gt;
Don't get me wrong though, Demmers doesn't have bad teas. They're affordable and you can find them in Cluj. And if your life doesn't depend on tea, they're a very good choice.&lt;br&gt;
But if you're like me and life literally revolves around tea, it's not the end goal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very good book that thought me a lot about teas was &lt;a href="https://www.bookdepository.com/Tea-Kevin-Gascoyne/9780228100270"&gt;Tea: History, Terroirs, Varieties&lt;/a&gt;. I also linked my favourite site to buy books from, free worldwide delivery, they're a life saver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, my journey has not ended, I have to personally go to those countries, and try the teas, brewed in their local spring waters, freshly picked, freshly roasted, take part of the process, learn more and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because tea was such an important thing in my life, I started collecting teaware, gaiwans, cups, teapots.&lt;br&gt;
So, one day, I was looking for movies/series/anime about tea, and I found it: &lt;a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/9996/Hyouge_Mono"&gt;Hyouge Mono&lt;/a&gt;. It's an anime with tea, but the main focus is teaware. I was thrilled by how they described teaware.&lt;br&gt;
What if... I make my own? I have a profound connection with tea, why shouldn't I share the connection with teaware?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, after a few weeks of looking, researching, I found a ceramic workshop in Cluj. I gathered my courage and paid a visit. I instantly became a regular.&lt;br&gt;
My first cup (I'll talk about it in a later post) was a success in my opinion, and so I made cups over cups over cups. With that, I've found my purpose in life.&lt;br&gt;
That after I die, I leave a few pieces of teaware that somebody will put his hands on and say "that's beautiful".
That's what I want to leave behind, beauty in the form of a teacup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I can go to the workshop only once a week, and now because of some works around the area I can't go until the end of August. That is way too little, it's not remotely enough to even have dreams, yet alone, achieve them. I want to spend tens of years, hours a day, practicing. That's the only way it can ever be good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, the end goal is, a studio of my own where I can spend hours a day, and a kiln. And who knows, probably a teashop where people can enjoy drinking from my cups.&lt;br&gt;
It will take quite a few years to achieve my dream, but it's a clear path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope it was a good read!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tea"></category><category term="about"></category><category term="tea"></category><category term="teaware"></category></entry></feed>