<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>On a Wooden Block - Teaware</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/feeds/teaware.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://onawoodenblock.com/</id><updated>2021-04-30T00:03:00+03:00</updated><subtitle>Tea freak, teaware admirer and keyboard masher.</subtitle><entry><title>I love cracks.</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/i-love-cracks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-30T00:03:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-04-30T00:03:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-04-30:/i-love-cracks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Waterglass and Iron Oxide, quick showoff.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, throughout my adventures with clay, I started playing with waterglass.&lt;br&gt;
I go to a workshop for ceramics and the person in charge, Andras, told me about it.&lt;br&gt;
So, I gave it a test round, came out quite great, and so I decided to make myself a chawan with the accumulated knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also love iron oxide (rust), I feel like it adds to the aestetique of age.&lt;br&gt;
I'm deeply, let me repeat myself, deeply in love with the philosophy and aestetique of wabi-sabi, and that's the style I pursue in my cups.&lt;br&gt;
I want them to feel raw, imperfect, not too complicated, not too simple. Fortunately, I haven't yet found it, I'm still in the pursuit of it, and I'm saying fortunately because the journey towards the perfect style is a heck of a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then, short intro, here are the cups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First try, to see what can iron oxide and waterglass do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/waterglass_test.jpg" width="760"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is the second cup. After seeing what I can do with it, this is one of the works I'm proud of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/chawan_waterglass.jpg" width="760"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you like them!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Teaware"></category><category term="chawan"></category><category term="teaware"></category></entry><entry><title>My very first teacup</title><link href="https://onawoodenblock.com/my-very-first-teacup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-04-18T12:08:00+03:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T12:08:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Rexu</name></author><id>tag:onawoodenblock.com,2021-04-18:/my-very-first-teacup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A story about my first teacup.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As written in a &lt;a href="/my-tea-journey.html"&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, because of tea and a &lt;a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/9996/Hyouge_Mono"&gt;certain anime&lt;/a&gt; I became obsessed with making my own teaware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, looking for ceramic workshops in Cluj. Somehow, I find one and I muster up my courage to go for a visit.&lt;br&gt;
I put myself on a chair and the guy in charge (we'll call him A) starts explaning about everything and guides me through every step in making a beautiful teacup.&lt;br&gt;
He tells me to start with a technique called "nerikomi", make a salami combining clays, then cut pieces, put them side by side to form a rectangle and then press it into a predefined form. Pressing it into a "biscuit" ceramic bowl is the easiest way of achieving a form. It's fired at 800-1000 degrees celsius and it absorbs moisture, so once I put in into form, it can easily separate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's what I do, I'm given multiple clays with similar shrinkage. Clay shrinks after moisture evaporates and if you make nerikomi and the shrinkage is too different, it will separate either when drying or biscuiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make a rectangle using white, brown and some black, and start pressing it into form, being VERY careful not to break anything. Afterwards I put a little circle foot on the bottom of the cup and with that three hours have passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, I await the next workshop which is two weeks later. The workshop used to be held twice a month before transitioning to twice a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next workshop comes, I carefully sandpaper the cup and make the form of another cup (which I probably won't talk about, didn't come out that great).&lt;br&gt;
And so, another two weeks pass, my cup was fired at 850&amp;deg;C and now it's time to glaze it. Because it's my very first cup and I want to see the pattern so I use a transparent glaze.&lt;br&gt;
Another two weeks, my cup is fired at 1200&amp;deg;C and it's finally ready. I can take it home and enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the story, it took quite a while to finish the cup, and I put at least 5 hours in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/first_cup1.jpg" width="760"&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/first_cup2.jpg" width="760"&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/first_cup3.jpg" width="760"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Teaware"></category><category term="teaware"></category><category term="teacup"></category></entry></feed>